# **Melissa Terry**

Santa Barbara, CA (805) 698-6349 mkterry@ucsb.edu linkedin.com/in/melissakayeterry/

As a recent graduate rooted in biochemistry, I focused my interest in computational biology and programming to optimize research outcomes. Alongside this, my background in customer service has equipped me with strong interpersonal skills and a knack for problem-solving. With experience in Python, SQL, and MATLAB, I am excited to apply and enhance these skills to derive valuable insights in a data analyst position.

# **EDUCATION**

- University of California, Santa Barbara
  - o Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry-Molecular Biology, Sept. 2021 Aug. 2023
- Santa Barbara City College
  - o Biology Major for Transfer, Sept. 2017 Aug. 2021

# **SKILLS**

- Python: Strong command of Python, including Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, and Matplotlib.
- MATLAB: Experience using numerical integration on systems of ODEs for dynamic modeling.
- **SQL:** Knowledgeable in writing SQL queries for performing CRUD operations within a relational database.
- AWS: Experience using various AWS services to support a database that leverages an event driven pipeline.
- Git: Proficient in utilizing Git for version control and collaborative coding.
- Data Analysis: Proficient in utilizing programming languages for data cleaning, wrangling, visualization, and interpretation.
- Data Visualization: Experience in creating visualizations that drive actionable insights.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### NOMAD GOODS, Santa Barbara, CA

Logistics Specialist, Jul 2018 - Dec 2019

- Managed daily operations, processing ~400 shipments per day using ShipStation.
- Led a team of 5, training and delegating tasks for efficient order processing and accurate shipments.
- Implemented order prioritization by date and quality control measures to minimize errors.

### SANTA BARBARA GYMNASTICS CLUB LLC., Santa Barbara, CA

Instructor/Camp Manager, Nov 2014 - Dec 2016

- Led engaging gymnastics classes for 15 children per class, fostering a safe learning environment.
- Efficiently managed payment tracking for ~100 client accounts using Excel, ensuring accurate records.
- Coordinated staff schedules and organized group rotations to efficiently manage class attendance.

### TERUN, Palo Alto, CA

Bartender/Server/Hostess, Sept 2013 - Oct 2014

- Demonstrated excellent customer service skills, ensuring client satisfaction through personalized interactions.
- Thrived in a fast-paced bar environment, serving up to 20 customers and managing drink orders for 5+ servers.
- Collaborated with the team to streamline operations and enhance customer satisfaction.